<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Amy Hanlon</title><link href="http://amygdalama.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://amygdalama.github.io/feeds/tags/career-management.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://amygdalama.github.io/</id><updated>2013-12-02T13:48:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Adventures in Miami: Bullish Conference 2013</title><link href="http://amygdalama.github.io/adventures-in-miami-bullish-conference-2013.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-12-02T13:48:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Amy Hanlon</name></author><id>tag:amygdalama.github.io,2013-12-02:adventures-in-miami-bullish-conference-2013.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="alt text" src="http://amygdalama.github.io/images/bullicorns.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Photo by Julie Lavoie)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adjusting to Real Life after a weekend in South Beach, filled with
mojito-flavored space popsicles, champagne, Cuban food, unicorn puzzles,
and badass, ambitious, feminist women is like coming down from some
fantastic drug-induced hallucination. This morning I was unpleasantly
surprised that there wasn't a sunkissed cabana man waiting to serve me
delicious iced coffee, and the absence of poolside complimentary wine
hour at 5pm will only deepen my wounds. (And yes! Cabana men are
real! Unfortunately for me they are all either teenagers or gay or both,
and even more unfortunately none agreed to move to Austin to volunteer
as my butler.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, we Bullicorns are well-equipped for aggressively
confronting this cabana man-less Real World, because alongside
&lt;a href="http://www.thegloss.com/2012/03/21/career/bullish-life-achieve-goals-and-glory-by-recreating-like-a-total-fcking-badass-126/"&gt;recreating like a total fucking badass&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.bullishconference.com/"&gt;BullCon&lt;/a&gt; was packed with
motivating workshops. Topics included negotiation with Ji Eun (Jamie)
Lee, who frequently speaks at women's conferences on the topic; planning
your 2014 and the top 10 principles of bullishness with Jen Dzuira,
organizer of the conference and writer of the &lt;em&gt;Bullish&lt;/em&gt; column; time
management with Laura Vanderkam, author of &lt;em&gt;What the Most Successful
People Do Before Breakfast&lt;/em&gt;;  all the tools to do all the things (and
the power of being your own assistant, at least if you don't have one)
with Haley Mlotek, publisher of &lt;em&gt;Worn&lt;/em&gt; magazine and Jen's virtual
assistant; and pitching yourself and your ideas (without selling out)
with Jennifer Wright, Editor-in-chief at the &lt;em&gt;New York Observer&lt;/em&gt;.
Write-ups on each of the workshops can be found on the &lt;a href="http://www.getbullish.com/tag/bullcon2013/"&gt;Bullish&lt;/a&gt; blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BullCon was the perfect balance of gentlewomanly recreation and
productivity, and I'm excited to see the progress each of us makes in
the next year. See you ladies in 2014 (and on the internet)!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bullish"></category><category term="career management"></category><category term="negotiation"></category><category term="pitching"></category><category term="time management"></category></entry></feed>