<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Amy Hanlon</title><link href="http://amygdalama.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://amygdalama.github.io/feeds/tags/diversity.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://amygdalama.github.io/</id><updated>2014-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>AlterConf: A Conference to Emulate</title><link href="http://amygdalama.github.io/alterconf.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amy Hanlon</name></author><id>tag:amygdalama.github.io,2014-10-05:alterconf.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I attended &lt;a href="http://www.alterconf.com/"&gt;AlterConf&lt;/a&gt;, a conference about diversity in the tech and gaming industries, hosted by &lt;a href="http://www.ashedryden.com/"&gt;Ashe Dryden&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talks were enlightening, personal, and hopeful:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thebitchwhocodes.com/"&gt;Stacey Mulcahy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cattsmall"&gt;Catt Small&lt;/a&gt; on lessons they've learned running the &lt;a href="http://codeliberation.org/"&gt;Code Liberation Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, an organization that offers free game development workshops for women&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://manamaneco.blogspot.com/"&gt;Manuel Marcano&lt;/a&gt; on avoiding Native American stereotypes in games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.davidpeter.me/"&gt;David Peter&lt;/a&gt; on what deafness is, his experiences being deaf, and what we can do to be more inclusive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://anewchallengerawaits.com/general/"&gt;Shawn Alexander Allen&lt;/a&gt; on how underrepresented game designers have used Kickstarter to crowdfund their games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://rubywankenoobie.tumblr.com/"&gt;Stephanie Morillo&lt;/a&gt; on her experiences learning to code while growing up in the Bronx and how lack of exposure is blocking entire communities from startups and the tech industry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://senongo.net/"&gt;Senongo Akpem&lt;/a&gt; on the booming tech scene in Nigeria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/chrisalgoo"&gt;Chris Algoo&lt;/a&gt; on lessons learned organizing diversity-focused game jams through &lt;a href="http://www.brooklyngamery.com/"&gt;Brooklyn Gamery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sinthetix"&gt;Aly Ferguson&lt;/a&gt; on how gaming has a tremendous impact in mental, physical, and social rehabilitation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://arlduc.org/"&gt;Arlene Ducao&lt;/a&gt; on her experiences with micro-discrimination at MIT Media Lab and the relationship between US startup culture and imperialism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AlterConf has the most diverse set of speakers I've ever seen at a conference. This is not a coincidence. I'd like to emphasize a few details of AlterConf that made the environment particularly safe and welcoming, in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;explicit focus on all aspects of diversity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AlterConf/status/506929157688000512"&gt;all gender restrooms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;preferred pronouns on nametags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;taped-off mobility zones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ADA accessible, and near ADA accessible public transportation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;real-time captioning (Lindsey Kuper wrote a great &lt;a href="http://composition.al/blog/2014/05/31/your-next-conference-should-have-real-time-captioning/"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about why !!Con provided this)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sign language interpreters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hyper-local (reduced travel costs for attendees and speakers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sliding-scale tickets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;speaker compensation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first-time speakers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.alterconf.com/code-of-conduct"&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;food and &lt;em&gt;non-alchoholic&lt;/em&gt; drinks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;content/trigger warnings when appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no forced networking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;side rooms available to take breaks from being social&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plenty of breaks between talks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;optional partners to walk with you to your subway station, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's clear that the organizers put a &lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt; of work into making the conference safe and accessible for everyone, and their work paid off in an exceptionally diverse set of speakers and attendees. This is what can happen when organizers shift their focus from providing social events and happy hours to making their conference safe and accessible.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="alterconf"></category><category term="diversity"></category><category term="conferences"></category></entry></feed>