<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Amy Hanlon</title><link href="http://amygdalama.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://amygdalama.github.io/feeds/hacker-school.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://amygdalama.github.io/</id><updated>2014-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Introducing Iron Maker Or Forger Or Something</title><link href="http://amygdalama.github.io/introducing-iron-maker-or-forger-or-something.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Amy Hanlon</name></author><id>tag:amygdalama.github.io,2014-04-19:introducing-iron-maker-or-forger-or-something.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The end of &lt;a href="https://www.hackerschool.com/"&gt;Hacker School&lt;/a&gt; is quickly approaching and a thousand kittens are crying tears of sadness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/cat-crying.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to maintain momentum and Never Graduate, I'm challenging myself and some other Hacker Schoolers to complete a programming project once a week for two(?) months.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This challenge is inspired by Iron Blogger, which requires participants to blog once a week, and if you miss a week, you owe $5. Mike Walker, from the Fall 2013 batch of Hacker School, &lt;a href="http://blog.lazerwalker.com/blog/2013/12/24/one-post-a-week-running-an-iron-blogger-challenge"&gt;wrote extensively&lt;/a&gt; about Iron Blogger.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference with Iron Maker, or Iron Forger, or Iron Something-Clever-That-Will-Hopefully-Come-To-Me-In-The-Near-Future, is that we will be completing small, self-contained programming projects, rather than writing blog posts.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, I want to work on projects that take about 4-8 hours to complete, and center around making, for lack of a better word, a &lt;em&gt;product&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Criteria&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/amygdalama/status/456950130286292992"&gt;asked Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for project ideas, but I hadn't yet figured out how to explicitly define criteria for what I was looking for. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/moss"&gt;Moss Collum&lt;/a&gt; responded with an excellent &lt;a href="http://makingcodespeak.com/2014/04/18/tiny-projects.html"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, which includes some defining characteristics of good projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short&lt;/strong&gt;: I can see interesting results within a few hours, and some results even sooner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End-to-end&lt;/strong&gt;: The project produces real software with a user-interface (even if it’s a simple one like a command-line script).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expandable&lt;/strong&gt;: Once I have some working code, it should be easy to think of new features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable&lt;/strong&gt;: There should be room to change requirements over time in ways that break my assumptions and test my code’s ability to evolve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fun&lt;/strong&gt;: The problem should be something I can care about enough to stay engaged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These projects are not intended to result in products that people will actually use. Instead, the intention is to get exposure to new tools and concepts and to practice making software design decisions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Suggested Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be maintaining a &lt;a href="https://github.com/amygdalama/programming-projects"&gt;list&lt;/a&gt; of suggested projects on GitHub. I'm trying to keep the list short, manageable, and high-quality, so I'm only adding projects that I'm committed to working on, and then for each project I'll be adding details on how long it took and what parts were fun/challenging/easy/boring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The repo also contains a list of resources with much more extensive project lists. If I'm missing any good resources, of if you've completed any small projects that have been particularly enlightening, please submit a pull request or create an issue! &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="hacker school"></category></entry><entry><title>Hacker School Day 2: Goals! Or, A Grasp For Sanity</title><link href="http://amygdalama.github.io/hacker-school-day-2-goals.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-12T10:02:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Amy Hanlon</name></author><id>tag:amygdalama.github.io,2014-02-12:hacker-school-day-2-goals.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have to admit day 1 of Hacker School was fairly overwhelming for me. With so many amazing people to talk to and interesting projects to
collaborate on I felt a bit like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="alt text" src="https://raw2.github.com/amygdalama/amygdalama.github.io/master/images/allthetennisballs.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Credit to Hacker School alumnus Alex Beaulne for finding this perfect
gif.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an attempt to regain a bit of sanity, yesterday I prioritized setting
goals for the batch and creating a semi-pubic to-do list. I also began
maintaining a list of learnings about how I can better approach Hacker
School and learning in general. My to-do list, goals, and learnings can
be found on my &lt;a href="https://github.com/amygdalama/hacker-school-progress"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, which I'll be updating at least daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to determine my goals, I answered the following questions, to
ensure that what I set out to accomplish aligned with my values and my
motivations for attending Hacker School. These lists are ranked somewhat
by importance, but probably aren't perfectly ordered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do I want to get out of Hacker School?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greater confidence, honesty, self-awareness, bravery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gain expertise in Python, Data Analysis, Machine Learning (currently
    beginner-/intermediate-level)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join a community of programmers/math nerds who will help motivate me
    to achieve greatness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frankly, a job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do I want to accomplish at Hacker School?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One large (1-month) project which
    requires pulling data from many sources and applying a recommender
    system, probably to recommend an optimal brunch spot for me, because
    brunch is awesome. This idea is inspired by &lt;a href="http://www.hilarymason.com/presentations-2/in-search-of-the-optimal-cheeseburger/"&gt;Hilary Mason&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A plethora of varying, small (1-day) analysis and machine learning
    projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog posts galore (3-5 per week) with a focus on writing
    tutorials/explaining benefits of various packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A successful pull request, contributing to an open source project or
    an existing tutorial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a Python package (maybe with functions based on Jaynes'
    &lt;em&gt;Probability Theory: The Logic of Science&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give a talk! (eeeep!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revamped website possibly using Pelican/GitHub pages (nonessential,
    not a priority)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Murdered out GitHub account (a pleasant side effect of all of the
    above)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="github"></category><category term="hacker school"></category></entry><entry><title>I moved cross-country for Hacker School and I'm only slightly convinced this is Real Life</title><link href="http://amygdalama.github.io/i-moved-cross-country-for-hacker-school-and-im-only-slightly-convinced-this-is-real-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-10T23:23:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Amy Hanlon</name></author><id>tag:amygdalama.github.io,2014-02-10:i-moved-cross-country-for-hacker-school-and-im-only-slightly-convinced-this-is-real-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Or, Hacker School: Day 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy Shit! I have been fairly silent over the past month because I got
accepted to &lt;a href="https://www.hackerschool.com/"&gt;Hacker School&lt;/a&gt; and had to figure out the logistics of
quitting my job, moving cross-country, and living in the most expensive
city in the States without a proper job for at least 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So allow me to re-iterate: Holy Shit! And somehow I did it and I'm alive
but not entirely certain it's not all just a dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was the first day of a possibly insane but probably brilliant
adventure. Hacker School is self-described as a writers' retreat for
programmers. I've heard other Hacker Schoolers struggle to explain it as
a day spa for programmers, a hippie commune programming cult (okay, that
one was me), not a school, not necessarily for &lt;a href="https://raw2.github.com/amygdalama/amygdalama.github.io/master/images/hackers-movie.jpg"&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; kind of
Hackers, and more. The Hacker School founders and facilitators have
written extensively about what Hacker School is and is not, so dig into
their blog if you're curious. It's difficult to define, and they do a
much better job than I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first day, I dedicated a good hour to getting my computer set up
properly (if you've seen my &lt;a href="http://mathamy.com/2013/12/27/wget-sanity-part-2-im-an-idiot-and-decided-to-switch-to-a-brewed-python-and-reinstall-the-scientific-stack-at-10pm/"&gt;wget&lt;/a&gt; posts, you'll know this
is something I've struggled with in the past). Then I had my first
attempt at pair programming in which I explained a few cool things about
&lt;a href="http://scikit-learn.org/"&gt;scikit-learn&lt;/a&gt; to another Hacker Schooler who had never used it
before. In turn she showed me some regression modeling in R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got to play with HS's resident Apple II. One of the other Hacker
Schoolers wrote a simple for loop to print out "DONG" 100 times. Why
would you do anything else?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="alt text" src="https://raw2.github.com/amygdalama/amygdalama.github.io/master/images/appleiidong.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am supremely honored and excited as Hell to be at Hacker School. For
the next three months, I will be surrounded by intellectually curious
nerds who are more thoughtful and self-aware than most people I know. I
hope I am brave and honest enough to confront the gaps in my knowledge,
ask questions, seek help, and ultimately get the most out of what will
be some of the most formidable months of my life. Which reminds me of
the Bene Gesserit litany:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I must not fear. Fear is the mind-killer. Fear is the little-death
that brings total obliteration. I will face my fear. I will permit it
to pass over me and through me. And when it has gone past me I will
turn to see fears path. Where the fear has gone there will be
nothing... Only I will remain.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><category term="hacker school"></category></entry></feed>